1. Because he was convinced of his own ____________ , Adam never accepted criticism. Ans: D. infallibility 2. Because she was so __________ , Mary rarely spoke in groups of people. Ans: A. reticent 3. She was unable to move her arm after the stroke; in addition, the stroke ___________ her ability to speak. Ans: C. impeded 4. While he was still_____________ , the doctors advised Phillip to remain home, lest he was contagious, even though his symptoms had receded. Ans: C. convalescing 5. Her last-minute vacation was ____________ compared to her usual trips. Ans: C. predictable 6. In searching for norms in the sense of authoritative standards of what ought to be, rather than in the sense of what is average and thus can be considered normal, normative ethics aims to ________. Ans: B. mitigate 7. With so many of America’s malls shutting down due to the financial crisis, there might soon be a significant dearth of locations in which teenagers can _____. Ans: E. ruminate 8. The young man always had to have the last word; he would rather be disliked than ______. Ans: A. gainsaid 9. Although she earned her fame for her striking murals, the artist felt that her sculpture merited greater _____. Ans: B. acclaim  10. Strange to think that for the majority of the 1950's, the _____ of nuclear holocaust was a daily part of people's lives. Ans: A. specter 